A racing second hand, a glittering shooting star!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مُذنّب لامع
Conan's logic is good medicine for hearts dried by modern society!
استنتاجات كونان دواء ممتاز للقلوب !التي جفّفها المجتمع الحديث
Today's point is evidence-finding! Don't overlook anything important!
!نقطة اليوم الأساسيّة هي البحث عن دليل !لا تغفلوا عن الأمر المهم
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
Beika Art Museum
متحف بيكا للفنون
Abstract Art of the World
فنّ العالم التجريدي
It was nice of my client to give me free passes for solving his case,
كانت تذاكر الدخول المجّانية التي أعطاني إيّاها عميلي بعد حلّ قضيّته بادرة لطيفة
but these make no sense!
!لكنّي لا أفهم شيئاً
Yeah, but they're still pretty!
غير مفهومة، لكنّها جميلة نوعاً ما
You serious?
تظنّين ذلك؟
I agree with you, old man.
أتّفق مع العمّ
What's that guy up to?
ما الذي يفعله ذاك الرجل؟
Please, sir! Don't touch the art! And smoking is prohibited!
!لا يمكنك سيّدي! لمس اللوحات ممنوع !كذلك، لا يمكنك التدخين
Oh, sorry...
...آسف
What a weirdo.
يا للشخص الغريب
Okay! Here goes! Catch it, you guys!
!هيّا، سأبدأ! أمسكوا بها
Why are we playing baseball and not soccer?!
لمَ نلعب كرة القاعدة؟ لمَ ليس كرة القدم؟
Conan! It's all yours!
!كونان! إنّها نحوك
Where are you aiming?!
!أين ضربتها؟
Are you all right?! I'm so sorry!
!أأنت بخيرٍ؟! آسفون
Oh? Didn't I see you at the...
...ماذا؟ ألستَ ذاك الرجل
You were drawing sketches?
كنتَ ترسم تخطيطات؟
Huh? He was drawing these just now?
ماذا؟ كان يرسم هذه الآن؟
Why do you always draw the same pictures?
لمَ ترسم نفس الصور باستمرار؟
Why... do I always...
...لمَ... باستمرار
I don't know...
لا أدري
Hey, Conan. Is he hurt?
كونان، هل تأذّى؟
Shall we call an ambulance?!
أنطلب الإسعاف؟
Are you serious?!
!أأنت جاد؟
Who... who am I?
من... من أنا؟
I can't even remember my name...
!لا أستطيع تذكّر اسمي حتّى
Does he have amnesia?!
أيعاني من فقدان ذاكرة؟
Because of me?!
!بسببي أنا؟
No! The ball hit his arm!
!كلا، أصابت الكرة ذراعه
My head hurts!
!رأسي يؤلمني
Are you all right?!
أأنت بخير؟
My head... my head hurts!
!رأسي... رأسي يؤلمني
Yamada General Hospital
مشفى يامادا العام
So, he really has amnesia?
يعاني من فقدان ذاكرة بالفعل إذاً؟
Yes. His headaches occur as his memory slowly returns.
أجل، يصيبه الصداع بينما ترجع ذاكرته تدريجياً
What a surprise...
يا للدهشة
What a shock...
هذا مُفاجئ
So, he still doesn't know who he is...
لا يزال يجهل من يكون ومن أين هو إذاً؟
Poor guy...
يا للمسكين
Don't worry! We notified the police, so we'll know soon enough!
لا تقلقوا، بلّغنا الشرطة لذا سوف نعرف سريعاً
Whoops! I forgot to leave his sketchbook!
!كلا! نسيتُ ترك دفتر رسمه
It's that man's, right?
هذا الدفتر له؟
Then let's go back!
لنرجع إذاً
You two, check the emergency exit!
!تفقّدا مخرج الطوارئ
Yes, sir!
حاضر
Did something happen?
أحصل أمرٌ ما؟
Actually, the patient you brought in just disappeared.
في الواقع، اختفى المريض الذي جلبتموه
I take it he didn't leave through the front door.
يبدو أنّه لم يغادر من المدخل بناءً على ردّة فعلكم
No, we haven't seen him.
نعم، لم نره
What about his clothes and things?
ماذا عن ثيابه وأمتعته؟
It looks like he changed clothes and took his things with him.
يبدو أنّه غيّر ثيابه، كما أخذ كلّ أمتعته
Did his memory return?! But then why would he disappear?
أرجعت ذاكرته؟ لكن لمَ قد يختفي عندها؟
Just where did he go?
أين ذهب بالضبط؟
Ready?! Here it comes!
!مستعدّون؟! سأبدأ
Ugh! Why aren't we playing soccer?!
يا إلهي، لمَ لا نلعب كرة القدم؟
Genta-kun! It's yours!
!غينتا-كن! إنّها نحوك
I got it! It's all mine!
أنا لها! سأمسكها
You okay, Genta?!
أأنت بخيرٍ يا غينتا؟
What the...
...هـ-هذا
It's the man from yesterday!
!إنّه الرجل المُسن من الأمس
Did the ball hit him again?!
!هل أصابته الكرة مجدداً؟
No!
!كلا
He was strangled with string or something!
!خُنق بما يشبه الحبل
No way!
!مستحيل
He was murdered?!
!أكانت جريمة قتل؟
Inspector, he was strangled to death, probably sometime last evening.
،حضرة المفتّش، يبدو أنّ سبب الوفاة هو الخنق قُتِل مساء الأمس غالباً
His pockets are empty.
جيوبه فارغة
Alright, Conan!
!أنت يا كونان
What's the big idea?! Bugging the inspector again, are ya?!
ما الذي تفعله؟! أتسبّب للمفتّش !المتاعب مُجدداً؟
No, no, Mori-kun. These children discovered the body.
كلا يا موري-كن، هؤلاء الأطفال هم من عثروا على الجثّة
The victim was here last night, too?
كان الضحيّة هنا بالأمس بمفرده إذاً؟
Yes!
!نعم
Perhaps the killer marked him and mugged him when he was alone...
لعلّ القاتل لاحظه، وهاجمه عندما كان بمفرده وسرق ماله
A robbery, huh?
عملية سرقة إذاً؟
Oh, brother...
...مهلكما
Say, Inspector! The victim's paint supplies are gone!
!حضرة المفتّش! اختفت أدوات الرسم للضحيّة
Paint supplies?
أدوات الرسم؟
His canvas and easel are gone, too!
اختفى لوح رسمه والحامل أيضاً
So is his paint box!
!كذلك صندوق الألوان
His bag, too!
!حقيبته أيضاً
He had such items?
كانت هذه مع الضحيّة؟
They must've been stolen as well.
لا بدّ أنّها سُرقت كذلك
Yeah, right! Nobody'd ever steal that junk, it'd just weigh 'em down!
مستحيل، لن يسرق أحد تلك الأدوات الرخيصة، ستُثقل عليه فحسب
Besides, one of his shoelaces is in a granny knot,
...وأيضاً
The ginkgo leaf in his shoe is strange, too.
ورقة الجنكة داخل حذائه مثيرة للغرابة أيضاً
There are no ginkgo trees here.
لا توجد أشجار جنكة في هذه المنطقة
Judging from his location, he must've been killed somewhere
بناءً على مكان الضحيّة، لا بدّ أنّه قُتل في مكانٍ ما
and tossed over the bridge during the night!
ثمّ أُلقي من على الجسر ليلاً
And why did he disappear from the hospital?
لمَ اختفى من المشفى أيضاً؟
This doesn't seem like any ordinary mugging to me!
لا تبدو هذه مجرّد !جريمة سرقة عادية أبداً
We need to find out who he is first...
بافتراض أنّها جريمة سرقة، علينا معرفة هويّة الضحيّة أوّلاً
Say, Inspector, I think this is actually--
...حضرة المفتّش، قد تكون هذه
Hey! I'll tolerate you getting in my way, but not the Inspector's!
،أنت! يكفي تدخّلك في تحقيقاتي !والآن تتدخّل في تحقيق المفتّش؟
But...
...لكن
Go play somewhere else!
!اذهب والعب بعيداً
Now, then, Inspector. Let's have a look at the victim.
إذاً حضرة المفتّش، لنلق نظرة على الضحيّة
Okay! Let's get started!
!حسناً، لنبدأ
What should we do?
ماذا تريدنا أن نفعل؟
We're the Junior Detective League!
!نحن فرقة فتيان التحرّي
Wow! Talk about dependable!
!مُذهل، أهلٌ للمسؤولية
Department Store
مركز تسوّق
So, behind the house is a pylon on the right and a factory on the left...
،خلف المنزل يميناً عمود كهربائيّ إذاً ...بينما يساراً يوجد مصنع
I get it!
!فهمت
So we just find that house!
!علينا إيجاد ذاك المنزل فحسب
Okay! Let's do it!
!حسنٌ، لنفعلها
Not here!
لا أراه
Nor here!
ولا هنا
It's not here, either! How about you, Ayumi-chan?
!ولا هنا أيضاً، ماذا عنك يا أيومي-تشان
I found it!
!وجدتُه
There it is! It even has a ginkgo tree!
!ها هو، إنّه ذاك !توجد شجرة جنكة حتّى
Okita House Cleaning
خدمة أوكيتا للتنظيف
"Hayase..."
..."هاياسي"
This car's brand new.
هذه السيّارة جديدة
Why does she want it so clean that there's not a single hair left?
لمَ تريد تنظيفها بحيث لا تبقى شعرة رغم أنّها ليست متّسخة حتّى؟
It's the same with the house.
الأمر نفسه داخل المنزل
She wants everything a person might touch wiped clean.
تريد مسح كلّ شيء يُحتمل أن يكون قد لمسه شخص
Don't tell me it's to erase fingerprints...
...أيمكن أنّ هذا لإزالة البصمات
Hey! What're you guys doing?!
!أنتم! ما الذي تفعلونه؟
Hayase Kimie (37)
(37) هاياسي كيمي
lt's still dirty. Go through again and-- oh?
...لا يزال متّسخاً، أعيدوا تنظيف الداخل
Hello!
عجباً
Here you are!
تفضّلوا
Oh, yes! I have some nice cookies! Just a minute!
!صحيح، لديّ بسكويت لذيذ !انتظروا قليلاً
Her apron's tied with a granny knot!
!عقدة مريلتها مربوطة رأسياً
The sofas and tables are different, and there's no tv.
الأريكة والطاولة ليست نفسها، ولا يوجد تلفاز
It's completely different from the pictures.
إنّها مختلفة تماماً عن الرسمة
Say, Miss. Did you remodel this room recently?
أخبريني يا عمّة، هل قمتِ بتحديث الغرفة مؤخراً؟
Yes. Why do you ask?
نعم، لمَ تسأل؟
Where's all the old stuff?
أين الأشياء السابقة؟
I threw it all away.
رميتُها كلّها
Is that painting new, too?
أتلك اللوحة جديدة أيضاً؟
Yes.
نعم
It arrived from the art gallery just two days ago.
وصلت من معرض الفنون قبل يومين فحسب
Isn't it lovely?
أليست جميلة؟
This is bad. It'll be hard to prove, now...
...هذا سيّئ، سيكون إثبات الأمر صعباً الآن
Incidentally, what did you want to ask me?
بالمناسبة يا أولاد، ما الذي أردتم الكلام معي بشأنه؟
Um, you go, Mitsuhiko-kun...
...حـ-حسناً، تكلّم يا ميتسوهيكو-كن
What was it, again?
ما كان يا ترى؟
Conan-kun! Look at that!
كونان-كن، انظر هناك
lt's him!
!إنّه ذاك الرجل
Hayase Tatsuo (47)
(47) هاياسي تاتسو
lt looks just like him!
ألا يشبهه تماماً؟
Even that characteristic nose is the same!
!حتّى أنفه المميّز مثله
Huh? He's wearing glasses!
!ماذا؟ يرتدي نظّارات
Who's he?
من ذاك الشخص؟
My husband.
زوجي
When did he pass away?
متى تُوفي؟
Why?
لمَ؟
He looks just like a murder victim discovered this morning!
يشبه رجلاً وجدته الشرطة مقتولاً صباح اليوم
Then it was someone else. My husband supposedly died a year ago.
لا بدّ أنّه كان رجلاً آخر، فزوجي قد تُوفّي قبل عام وفقما يُفترض
Supposedly?
وفقما يُفترض؟
Disaster disappearance?
اختفاء في كارثة؟
A person is normally presumed dead after going missing for seven years,
يُعدّ الشخص ميتاً إذا اختفى بشكل عاديّ لسبع سنوات في العادة
but people in natural disasters or shipwrecks
لكنّ الناس الذي يختفون أثناء كوارث طبيعية أو حوادث غرق سفن
are presumed dead after only one year.
يُعدّون موتى بعد مرور عامٍ فحسب
Come to think of it, a rich banker by the name of Hayase
على ذكر ذلك، كان هناك رجل ...يعمل في مصرف يُدعى هاياسي
was caught in an avalanche and went missing a year ago...
علق في انهيار ثلجيّ واُعتبر مفقوداً قبل عام
Yeah! That's him!
!أجل! ذاك هو
You have a good memory, Dad!
!من المُبهر أنّك تذكرته يا أبي
That's why I'm such a great detective.
هذه من سمات المتحرّي العظيم
Back then, there were rumors that he embezzled huge sums of money.
آنذاك، انتشرت شائعات عن اختلاس هاياسي هذا لأموال طائلة
He was just about to be investigated,
كانوا على وشك التحقيق معه
so the authorities figured it was a sham at first.
لذا ظنّت السلطات أنّه اختفاء مُصطنع
The embezzled money couldn't be tracked down,
لم يستطيعوا تعقّب مكان الأموال المُختلسة
so it was assumed he disappeared with it.
فافترضوا أنّه اختفى معها
But, it was eventually called a disaster disappearance?
لكن في النهاية اعتبروه اختفاءً في كارثة؟
Yeah.
نعم
Anyway, Conan. Have you told Inspector Megure?
بأيّ حال يا كونان، هل أخبرت المفتّش ميغوري؟
Yeah! He had her verify the body!
نعم! جعلها تتحقق من الجثّة
District Police Station - Charnel
مركز شرطة المنطقة - المشرحة
He resembles my husband, but it's not him.
يشبهه، لكنّه ليس زوجي بل شخصٌ مختلف
Say, does the late Hayase-san have any relatives?
هل كان لهاياسي-سان الراحل أيّ أقارب؟
A father, or mother, or siblings?
أب أو أمّ أو إخوة؟
No. He had no relatives. Why do you ask?
،كلا، لم يكن لديه أيّ أقارب لمَ تسأل؟
No reason...
...لا سبب
In other words, you're the only one who can verify his body?
أي أنّكِ الوحيدة التي تستطيع تأكيد هويّته؟
I suppose so.
يبدو ذلك
No smoking!
!أنت! لا تدخّن
Sorry...
...آ-آسف
Incidentally, did Mr. Hayase do paintings?
بالمناسبة، هل كان السيّد هاياسي يحبّ الرسم؟
Yeah! We can check the fingerprints on his old things!
يمكننا التحقّق من البصمات إذا حصلنا على أغراضه القديمة
Right, Inspector?!
صحيح حضرة المفتّش؟
Yes.
أجل
My husband did indeed paint.
كان زوجي يهوى الرسم حقّاً
He was painting in the mountains when the avalanche struck.
كان يرسم في الجبال عندما وقع الانهيار الثلجيّ قبل عام
But I threw out all his things.
لكنّي تخلّصتُ من كلّ أغراضه
All of them?
كلّها؟
The media and society started to condemn me, too,
لامني الإعلام والمجتمع
for the whole embezzlement thing.
بسبب قضيّة الاختلاس أيضاً وضايقوني
I wanted to forget my husband quickly.
أردتُ نسيان زوجي أسرع ما يمكن
In the end, all we can do is take her word for it...
في النهاية، كلّ ما يسعنا هو تصديق ما قالته
No! There's no doubt that the victim is Hayase Tatsuo-san!
كلّا، لا شكّ أنّ ذاك الضحيّة !كان هاياسي تاتسو-سان
There's gotta be some way to prove it!
ألا توجد طريقة لإثبات ذلك؟
Hello!
!مرحباً
Oh...
...عجباً
Sorry! We left something here last time!
المعذرة، نسينا شيئاً في اليوم السابق
Those cookies earlier were so good!
!كان البسكويت وقتها لذيذاً جدّاً
We'd love to have more!
!نريد أكله مجدداً
Oh, is that what you "left" here?
هذا الشيء الذي نسيتموه هنا؟
Bingo!
!صحيح
Just a minute!
انتظروا قليلاً
Are there any traces left that the victim was here?!
أبقيت أيّ آثار على قدوم الضحيّة هنا؟
What're you doing, Conan?
ما الذي تفعله يا كونان؟
Some kind of burn mark...
...أثر احتراق
Ginkgo leaves...
...أوراق جنكة
If they're lying here, then they'd come inside if the window was open...
تجمّعها هنا يعني أنّها ستدخل إذا كانت النافذة مفتوحة
Wait a minute! The leaf, the window, the burn mark,
...لحظة! الورقة والنافذة وأثر الحرق
the glasses-less victim, and the painting on the wall!
،الضحيّة الذي لم يضع نظّاراته !كما الرسمة على الحائط
I've finally found it!
!وجدتُه أخيراً
Proof that Hayase-san returned here with his memory intact!
دليل عودة هاياسي-سان لهذا المنزل !بعدما رجعت ذاكرته
Inspector Megure! The victim is unquestionably Hayase Tatsuo-san!
مفتّش ميغوري! ذاك الضحيّة هو !هاياسي تاتسو-سان بلا شكّ
I've finally found proof of it!
!وجدتُ دليلاً على ذلك أخيراً
What?! Really, Mori-kun?!
!ماذا؟! حقّاً يا موري-كن؟
Seriously, Inspector Megure?!
!حقّاً سيّدي المفتّش؟
Yes! Come immediately, Mori-kun!
نعم، تعال بأسرع ما يمكن يا موري-كن
Now, what is this all about?!
...ما الذي يعنيه هذا؟ حتّى لو كنتم الشرطة
I understand how you feel. Mori-kun will explain...
...أتفهّم مشاعرك، سيوضّح موري-كن
But I thought you were going to--
...لكن ظننتَ أنّك من سيوضّح
But, I guess not.
...قد لا يعجبك ذلك
Allow me to shed light on the truth behind this incident.
لكن سأسلّط أنا المتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو النور على حقيقة هذه القضيّة
One year ago, Mr. Hayase went into the mountains to paint
قبل عام، ذهب السيّد هاياسي للجبال للرسم
and was caught in an avalanche.
وعلق في انهيار ثلجيّ
He luckily survived, but lost his memory.
نجا لحسن الحظّ، لكن فقد ذاكرته
He then walked all over as a wandering artist,
أصبح يتجوّل بعدها في مختلف الأرجاء كرسّام متجوّل
unconsciously drawing his house all the while.
ويرسم لوحات لمنزله طوال الوقت دون إدراكه
A year passed, and he was judged to have disappeared by disaster.
مضى عام على الحادثة، وتمّ اعتبار السيّد هاياسي ميتاً في كارثة طبيعية
In short, his wife inherited his estate.
أي أنّ الزوجة سترث ممتلكاته
So?
وما في ذلك؟
So, you couldn't have him showing up now!
!لذا سيكون ظهوره الآن مشكلةً لك
What do you mean, Mori-kun?
ما قصدك يا موري-كن؟
Her inheritance likely included the missing money he had embezzled!
تضمّن ميراثه غالباً المال المفقود الذي قام باختلاسه
So, she killed Mr. Hayase when he returned yesterday, memory intact!
لذا، قامت بقتل السيّد هاياسي عندما ...رجع بالأمس هنا
So she could keep all the money!
!كي تحتفظ بالمال لنفسها
Are you serious, Mori-kun?!
!ما الذي تقوله يا موري-كن؟
My husband died in the mountains a year ago.
تُوفي زوجي في الجبال قبل عام
Or do you have proof he was alive?
أم لديك دليلٌ على أنّه كان حيّاً؟
You're right, I don't. That's because you disposed of all of his things.
صحيح، لا دليل لديّ، فأنتِ قد تخلّصتِ من كلّ أغراضه الشخصيّة
Naturally, you removed all possible fingerprints and hairs, too!
أزلتِ كلّ البصمات وبقايا الشعر التي يُحتمل أنّها بقيت بالطبع
You even hired a cleaning company to be extra sure!
عيّنتِ شركة تنظيف خاصّة من باب الحيطة حتّى
Which means you can't prove anything.
ما يعني أنّك لا تستطيع إثبات شيء
But, the victim left behind a connection with you:
لكن، بقي مع الضحيّة ما يصله بك
a gingko leaf in his shoe.
ورقة جنكة في فردة حذائه
There were no gingko trees where he was found.
لم تكن هناك أشجار جنكة في المكان الذي وُجِد فيه
Yes, there's a gingko tree next to my house... and all over Tokyo, too!
...أجل، توجد شجرة جنكة في منزلي كما في كلّ أرجاء طوكيو
One other thing, for some reason, only one of the victim's shoelaces
أمرٌ إضافيّ، لسببٍ ما كانت عقدة ...إحدى فردتي حذاء الضحيّة
was in a granny knot... just like your apron!
مربوطة بشكل رأسي
You're right!
!إنّها الحقيقة
Now that you mention it...
...بذكرك ذلك، تبدو فعلاً
Probably, when you put his shoes on after killing him,
،على الأرجح، عندما ألبستِه حذاءه عقب قتله
you noticed one was untied!
!لاحظتِ انحلال ربطة فردة
Not wanting to be suspected, you decided to tie it.
لم تريدي أن تثيري الشبهة لأمرٍ تافه كهذا، فقرّرتِ ربطها
Claiming I did it because of a granny knot? Hilarious.
تدّعي أنّي المجرمة بسبب عقدة رأسية؟ مثير للضحك
I'll have no more of these insults! I'll take you to court!
!لن أسمح لك بإهانتي أكثر! سأقاضيك جديّاً
Dad...
...أ-أبي
Are you sure about this, Mori-kun? You have proof, I hope?!
أأنت واثقٌ من هذا يا موري-كن؟ لديك دليل بالفعل، صحيح؟
Well, then, let me get to the real point.
إذاً، لننتقل لصلب الموضوع
Ran! Stand in front of the painting!
!ران، قفي أمام اللوحة
Me?
أنا؟
Yes.
نعم
Okay...
حسناً
Like this?
هكذا جيّد؟
That's just fine.
أجل، يكفي
Now, Miss. Was Mr. Hayase a heavy smoker?
الآن أخبريني يا سيّدة، أكان السيّد هاياسي مدخناً شرهاً؟
That's right.
صحيح
And you hate cigarettes, correct?
وأنتِ تكرهين التدخين، أليس كذلك؟
No smoking!
!أنت! لا تدخّن
Sorry...
...آ-آسف
What about it?
وما في ذلك؟
Mr. Hayase, after regaining his memory and leaving the hospital,
...بعد رجوع ذاكرته ومغادرته المشفى
stood in front of this painting, cigarette in mouth.
وقف السيّد هاياسي أمام هذه الرسمة في المنزل
Naturally, you opened the window.
توجّهتِ لفتح نافذة بما أنّك تكرهين التدخين بالطبع
Several ginkgo leaves likely fell inside then.
سقطت بضعة أوراق جنكة داخل المنزل وقتها غالباً
One got stuck to his foot while he was inside the house.
التصقت إحداها بقدم السيّد هاياسي عندما كان داخل هذا المنزل
But how do you know he was smoking there?
لكن كيف عرفت أنّه كان يدخّن هناك؟
Because of the burn mark on the wooden cabinet.
بسبب أثر الحرق على المنضدة الخشبية
As there was no ashtray in the house, he put it out there.
،لم تكن هناك منفضة سجائر في المنزل فأطفأها عليها
I hope you're not going to make me laugh by saying that's your proof.
لن تضحكني بادّعاء أنّ أثر الحرق ذاك هو دليلك، صحيح؟
Miss, was Mr. Hayase near-sighted?
سيّدتي، أكان السيّد هاياسي يعاني من قصر نظر؟
Yes.
صحيح
Ran, think back.
ران، تذكّري
Look at that painting the way he did at the Beika Art Museum.
انظري للوحة مثلما فعل هو في متحف بيكا للفنون
I think he got near it and--
...أظنّه اقترب، ثمّ
Stop!
!توقّفي
What is it?
ما-ماذا؟
I get it! His fingerprints, Dad!
!فهمت! البصمات يا أبي
Fingerprints? Are you saying there are some on that painting?
البصمات؟ أتقصدين أنّه توجد بصمات على تلك اللوحة؟
But you said she cleaned the whole place of fingerprints and hair!
لكنّك قلت أنّ الزوجة أزالت !كلّ البصمات والشعر من المنزل
Yes. She even hired a cleaning company.
أجل، قامت بتعيين شركة تنظيف حتّى
But think about it, Inspector.
لكن حضرة المفتّش، أمعن التفكير
No professional would wipe down a bare painting.
لن يُقدم متخصصو تنظيف على مسح لوحة فنّية
That's true...
...مـ-معك حق
But, if he had a habit of grabbing paintings, she would've known!
لكن إذا كان من عادة السيّد هاياسي !الإمساك باللوحات عند النظر لها، فستعرف السيّدة
No. That habit began after he lost his memory.
كلا، ظهرت عادته هذه بعدما فقد ذاكرته
Before he got amnesia, Mr. Hayase wore glasses for his near-sightedness.
كان السيّد هاياسي يرتدّي نظارات قصر نظر قبل إصابته بفقدان الذاكرة
But, he lost them in the avalanche.
لكنّه فقدها في الانهيار الثلجيّ
After that, he started getting close to paintings because of his poor vision.
بعدها، أصبح يقترب من اللوحات بسبب بصره الضعيف
And he formed a habit of grabbing them to get a good look.
وتشكّلت عادة إمساكه بها ليمعن النظر
When Mr. Hayase returned here and looked at the painting,
،عندما رجع السيّد هاياسي لهذا المنزل ونظر للوحة
his wife likely opened the window to air out the smoke.
توجّهت زوجته غالباً لفتح النافذة لتهوية الغرفة من الدخان
As her back was to him, she probably didn't notice this.
وبينما كانت تعطيه ظهرها، لم تنتبه للأمر على الأرجح
So, she overlooked it?
لذا غفلت عن ذلك؟
Miss. Can you explain why your husband's fingerprints
سيّدتي، هل يمكنك تفسير ...وجود بصمات الضحيّة
are on a picture you put up two days ago?
على لوحة وصلتك قبل مجرّد يومين؟
Takagi-kun! Call the examiners! Check for prints!
!تاكاغي-كن! اطلب فريق التحليل !اجعلهم يراجعون البصمات
Right!
!حاضر
I concede.
أستسلم
He did come here. It's all as the detective said.
أتى هنا فعلاً، كان كلّ شيء كما قال المتحرّي
I killed him. I drugged his coffee and strangled him with a rope.
قتلتُه
Still, why did you dump him in such a conspicuous spot?
لكن لمَ ألقيتِه في مكان مكشوف بحيث يُعثر عليه فوراً؟
I didn't want to wait any longer!
!لم أرد الانتظار أطول
He was finally classified as missing and I got his embezzled money!
تمّ اعتباره ميتاً أخيراً !وحصلتُ على ماله المُختلس
If people learned he was alive, amnesia or not,
إذا تسرّب أنّه كان حيّاً، سواءً عانى من فقدان ذاكرة أم لا
he might've lost all his money!
!سيجرون تحقيقاً بالتأكيد، وقد يأخذون المال كلّه
Seriously! I suffered because my husband was an embezzler...
لا تعبثوا معي، ذقتُ أنواع الألم والمضايقات ...بسبب عملية اختلاسه
That money was mine!
!كان ذلك المال لي
I wanted to get my time, and life, back!
!أردتُ استرجاع وقتي، استرجاع حياتي
You'll have plenty of time. Behind bars, that is.
،ستنعمين بالكثير من الوقت وراء القضبان
Way to go, Dad! You even solved the missing-persons case!
كما يُتوقع منك يا أبي! حللتَ لغز قضيّة شخص مفقود حتّى
Maybe I should hire you, too...
...ربما عليّ توكيلك أيضاً
Huh? Did someone go missing?
ماذا؟ هل هناك أحد مفقود؟
You know who!
!إنّه ذاك الشخص
That lousy Shinichi'll never come back unless I look for him!
شينتشي الهارب لن يرجع أبداً ما لم نبحث عنه
I hope he stays missing forever!
!فليبق مفقوداً للأبد
You know the score, all right!
تدرك الوضع على الأقل
Shiina-kun? What're you doing? What's with that car?
ما الذي تفعله يا شينا-كن؟ ما قصّة تلك السيّارة؟
Come on, Shiina-kun! Say something, will ya?!
!شينا-كن، ما بك؟ أجبني على الأقل
Minami-chan's been--
...مينامي-تشان، مينامي-تشان قد
kidnapped!
!اختُطِفت
Darn it! A kidnapping right before my eyes?!
!تبّاً! اختطاف أمام ناظري
On the next Conan:
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
"The Popular Artist Abduction Case (Part 1)."
قضيّة اختطاف الفنّانين الشهيرين (الجزء الأوّل)
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Two-Mix.
"تو-ميكس"
Next episode that popular group shows up.
ستظهر تلك الفرقة الشهيرة في الحلقة القادمة
Conan, what's your relationship with Two-Mix?
كونان، ما علاقتك بـ تو-ميكس؟